Running an agency is not easy. You have
to manage your clients and compete with
other competitors at the same time. But
trust me, your competitors aren't
better. They're just faster and smarter
at managing projects than you. While
you're buried in messy project threads
and scattered tools, they are winning
clients on autopilot. This video is all
about guiding you to the path to success
and helping you quietly turn every new
client into a repeat one. Like them,
managing your client's project starts
when they say, "Let's do it." and ends
when your work earns their final seal of
approval. Between the handshake and the
happy client, there is a minefield of
tasks. missed deadlines, forgotten
follow-ups, and at least one person
yelling, "Wait, who was supposed to do
that?" If your current workflow is a
mess, and you're just trying to survive
each week, there is a better way. Let's
break this down from an agency's
perspective.
First things first, you need that
payment. That's when the project really
kicks off. Then comes the real deal,
keeping everything organized. You've got
tasks to assign, deadlines to watch, and
progress to track. And through it all,
your client can't be left in the dark.
They need to stay in the loop with all
the updates, changes, and approvals.
Now, imagine this entire process
automated. In this video, I'll show you
exactly how to take payments for your
services using Payatic. Organize your
project with Fluent Boards and automate
the entire process from payment
confirmation to client updates with
Fluent CRM step by step. So, let's start
with the first critical step, client
payment setup.
For that, my choice is Payatic because
it's super simple to work with. I can
either build a form from scratch, choose
a readymade template, or maybe import
one within seconds. Since I've already
created my payment authorization form,
let me quickly show you how it looks.
So, as you can see, it has all the
essentials, name, email, package
options,
and a payment method. Perfect for
collecting client payments.
Now to make this whole process smarter,
I need to connect with Fluent CRM.
Before that, let me check whether the
integration is enabled or not. Let's
open the integration and spot Fluent
CRM. Well, as you can see, it's not
enabled yet. So, what I'll do is I'll
just toggle it on, and we're good to go.
It's time to head back to the form. Here
I need to set up a feed to link this
form to Fluent CRM. So I'll go to the
integrations,
hit the add button, and Fluent CRM shows
up as an option. So let's go with that.
The feed name looks good.
I'll select the Fluent CRM list where
new client info will be added after form
submission and map the fields to make
sure everything stays synced.
Okay. Then I will choose some tags
and take the boxes that fit my vision.
The feed is already enabled. So, all I
need to do is hit the create button and
the process completes here. Now, I'll
grab the form short code and paste it on
my payment page.
And just like that, it's done.
From now on, whenever I finalize a
project with a client, they can access
my page and make their payment with
ease. As I have already discussed with a
client and he's waiting on the other
end. Let me show you how it works.
Here's my form. My client will just fill
in the details and move to the payment.
From there, they will just provide the
details and hit pay to confirm the
payments.
That's it. This is one of many
occurrences. And as an agency owner, I'm
going to create an automation now so
that every time someone submits the
payment form, they get a reply
automatically. So let's go to Fluent CRM
and open the automation. I will hit the
new automation and then select create
from scratch. Here I have a couple of
triggers to get started, but I will go
with list applied.
After that, I will handpick the list I
used in the feed creation. But if you
want, you can go for other triggers and
adjust the settings according to your
needs. Oh, I forgot to name my
automation. So, I will cut the existing
one and write it as payment confirmation
automation.
And of course, save it.
Now, each time a payment comes in, the
contact gets added and the automation
fires up. The next step is to notify the
client about starting their project.
It's also a great opportunity to greet
them warmly, introduce them to other
services, and confirm that everything
went through smoothly. For that, I will
pick a custom email to craft a perfect
email for my clients. Here I will give
it a clear internal label and write a
subject line that aligns with their
action. Okay. Next I have the email
body. So this is where all the
information is stored and Fluent CRM
allows me to write, add or embed
anything I want using the email editor.
Besides, I can also use short codes to
fetch any information I want
automatically.
And to fasten this process, I have
created an email previously and saved it
as a template. So this time I will just
import a template to keep it simple.
Look at that. It's imported and looks
pretty sleek. I will just save the
changes. And that takes me back to the
automation page. So since it's in the
draft mode, I will switch it to
published.
And that sums up the whole process. From
now on, every client who submits a
payment form gets added to the CRM and
receives a confirmation email all on
autopilot.
The payment is just the starting point
of your project's journey. So once you
start working on it, the first thing you
need to do is get your project work
sorted. And Flintboards makes it a
breeze. And that's also using its free
version. Let's organize my project work
task by task. As you can see, some of
the projects I am working on are already
there. Since I'm starting with a fresh
one, let me just tap on add board.
I'll just name my project board.
And as I already crafted my project
details, what I'll do is I'll just paste
it into the description box.
Okay? So this will help my team members
to get an overview of the project right
from the start. So let's save it.
One boards gives me a clean setup right
away. Three stages and a blank canvas to
work with. But it's not limited to this.
I can create as many stages as my
project demands effortlessly and also
rename the existing ones if needed.
See? Well, it's time to organize my
tasks. If I click on the add task, I
will need to give it a title
and save it. Tapping on it gives me
access to everything I need to customize
the task, even with the free version.
The title is shining at the top.
Okay. So, what I'm going to do is I'm
going to add a due date for this task,
set a priority level,
add some relevant levels,
and write a description that will make
it easier for my team members to follow.
To make things even smoother for my
team, I'm linking the client CRM profile
right into the task. So all relevant
info is right there. There are other
smart options too like I can join as an
assigne,
move tasks between stages,
enable watch mode for realtime updates,
and even change task covers to visually
highlight the important stuff. I can
also archive the task if I need to. And
as you can see, my first task is ready
to be assigned to my team members. So,
let me do it with ease. Well, the first
task is sorted. Just like that, I'm
going to create tasks and organize this
board to manage my project with my team
members. In the meantime, feel free to
grab some coffee while the board takes
shape.
Now, take a look at this project board
I've prepared. As you can see, it's
clean, organized, and every task has a
clear assigne. Everyone knows what they
need to do, when to do it, and how it
connects to the bigger picture. Plus,
I've linked the client CRM profile
directly to the board. So, my entire
team has access to relevant client
details without switching tools or
digging through notes. With the project
work sorted, now it's time to make sure
your client knows what's happening
without writing update emails 10 times a
week. I'm going to do it using Fluent
CRM and Fluent Boards, the perfect combo
that automates a project communication.
All right, let's move on to the fun
part, automation.
Just like before, I'll open the
automation panel. Okay, I can choose
from a list of templates or start from
scratch. This time what I'm going to do
is I'm starting from scratch so you can
see the entire process step by step. Now
if I move to fluent boards I get access
to two key triggers. The first one fires
when a contact is added to a task. That
means whenever I assign someone on my
team to a new task, they get notified
automatically. No need for the messages,
emails, or a reminder. The second
trigger is even more powerful. It
activates when a task moves from one
stage to another. That's exactly what I
need to keep my clients updated about
the progress of their project in real
time. So, since this tutorial is more
about client communication, I'm going
with a state change trigger.
I'll name this automation state changed
update, but of course feel free to call
it whatever works for you. Then I'll
select the project board this automation
should apply to followed by defining the
from stage and the target stage.
This way anytime a task moves between
those two specific stages the automation
gets triggered.
Lastly, I will take the check box and
save the settings.
Now, it's time to notify the client.
I'll pick a custom email option. Just
like I did earlier, I'll import a
pre-written email template.
Okay. Tweak it if necessary and save the
changes. One final tap and the
automation is live.
And just like that, whenever the task
moves, the connected client contact gets
a notification without me lifting a
finger. This is how from here on my
clients stay informed without my team
sending a single manual update.
Keeping clients notified is important,
but asking for their feedback whenever a
task is completed is crucial. My next
automation is going to cover this. Just
as I did earlier, I will pick the state
change trigger and set the target stage
to complete.
This way whenever any task is moved to
the completed stage the automation will
kick off as I want to get the feedback
from my client. Now I'm going to take a
custom email and personalize it exactly
the way my project requires with all the
details.
Great. Looks perfect.
Once my clients get notified about the
changes, what about getting feedback
from them? Well, don't worry. Let's just
embed a previously created form link
into the email so my client can submit
his feedback.
And after submitting the form, it will
be directly added to my project board as
a task. If you want to know more about
it, you can check the short tutorial on
it. After that, go ahead and give it a
green signal to get things rolling.
And that's how you automate the project
update, collect clients feedback, and
run your project smoothly using Fluent
CRM.
If you want to build a sustainable
business, you must try to create
longlasting relationships with your
clients. What can be better than doing
it automatically? Before wrapping things
up, I'm going to show you how you can
nurture your clients with regular
updates and create more upsell or
cross-selling opportunities using
automation even after completing the
client's project. Let's trigger the
automation with a tag applied. From
here, name this automation so it's
easier to find later.
Select the tag,
define a condition, and hit save.
Since this is the first email after
project completion, it's a great time to
say thanks. I'll choose a custom email
and put in a pre-built thank you
template.
Okay, perfect.
Next, setting the waiting period, say 3
to 5 days before sending the next email.
Meanwhile, let's prepare a personalized
offer tailored to the client. But here's
the smart part. We can check if they
open the thank you email.
For that, let's add a condition and set
the data properties.
Based on their action, my next move will
be planned. In case a client has opened
the email, go ahead and grab another
custom email and send them a
personalized offer just for them.
But if they didn't open it, I'll add
them to a nurturing sequence to
gradually increase interest. As you can
see, everything's in place. So, let's
make the automation live and let the
system take care of the rest. As simple
as it looks. So, there you have it. From
payment to project updates to feedback
and follow-ups, your entire client
journey just got a major upgrade with
Fluent CRM automation. With Fluent CRM
and Fluent Boards working in sync,
you're not just managing projects,
you're building better client
relationship faster. If this made your
workflow smoother, show some love with a
like and subscribe. And if you've got
questions or use cases you want me to
cover, drop them in the comments. I'd
love to hear how you're planning to
automate your agency next. So until next
time, stay organized, stay efficient,
and keep growing with Fluent CRM. Grab
it now.